Blue, 18.
Set. Hit. Hit.
Zach. Zach. Crossbuck 30.
Crossbuck 30.
Crossbuck 30. Crossbuck 30.
- Ready?
- Ready.
The Eagles
will have to go for it on fourth down...
...with just 42 seconds left in the
football game and no timeouts.
Coach Grant Taylor can get
his first winning season...
...for the Shiloh Christian Academy
if they can pull this play off.
Blue, 18. Set, hit.
Zach Avery will take the snap.
He pitches back to Jacob Hall.
Jacob's gonna try to pass it. He's got
Jeremy Johnson going down the field.
But here come the Tigers.
Throw it, Jacob.
Jacob's gonna try
to tuck it and run.
And he's gonna be taken down
at the 40-yard line...
...stopped there
by Lewis Slaughter.
Jeremy Johnson was wide open
down the field.
If he'd only had a few seconds
more to throw the football...
...this game might have had
a different outcome.
As it is, the Tigers
will take over now...
...and will no doubt take a knee
to run out the clock...
...thus ending Coach Grant Taylor's bid
for his first winning season in six years.
Now he'll have to wait
until next season...
...for that all-elusive
winning record.
That's if they let him
come back next year.
Hi.
Get them, Claire.
Hey, Grant.
Come on, y'all. Quit talking.
Let's go, let's go, let's go. Hurry.
What?
You gotta be kidding me.
This had better be a joke.
Nope.
Mandy said he came in
this morning, got his papers.
Wait. A player can't just transfer
to another school to play football.
He's gotta make
a change of address.
He did. He's moving in
with his dad.
I can't believe that. This is
the third time this has happened.
Spend three years pouring into them,
and what do they do
when they get to their senior year?
They transfer
to a rival school. Why?
Well, because at the end
of the season
nobody wants to be on TV going,
"We're number six, baby.
We're number six."
Well, you asked.
Just had to go there, didn't you?
Coach, is it true Darren
switched to Tucker?
We'll talk about it
in a minute, Brock.
So it's true?
We'll talk about it in a minute.
Huddle up.
Coach, is it true
that Darren transferred to Tucker?
I got word this morning that
Darren did transfer to Tucker.
- God.
- Oh, my God.
There goes the season.
The season hasn't started
and will be whatever we make it.
Who's gonna take his place?
He scored a third of our points last year.
You let me worry about that. We're not
starting off the season as if it's doomsday.
- Nobody's irreplaceable.
- Darren is.
Darren is not. There's more to a good
football team than a running back.
If anything, this ought to push you
to take up the slack.
Stop worrying about Darren.
Get out there and start your drills.
We got a game to play
this Friday night.
All right, let's go, Shiloh.
Come on. Let's go.
All right, guys.
Why'd you park
all the way out there?
Had to. It died again.
Why don't we get a new battery?
I'll get Brady to help me tomorrow
morning. I don't wanna think about it now.
Do you want me to
take a look at it for you?
Stop it.
Oh, sweetheart...
Grant, I don't know what that smell is.
I've scrubbed everything I can.
- It's terrible.
- I know it is, but what else can I do?
I don't even know
where it's coming from.
Well, this day stunk.
Why shouldn't my house?
- What do you mean?
- Darren transferred to Tucker.
What? He did not.
Yep. Came by and got his papers,
didn't even say goodbye.
- Why?
- Why do you think?
Didn't see a chance
of winning at Shiloh.
But it ain't like Tucker's gonna
guarantee him a scholarship.
- Oh, I bet the boys are frustrated.
- More than you know.
I meant to throw that away.
Did you think you were pregnant?
I don't know. I just wanna
be pregnant so bad...
...that my mind plays tricks on me.
You know, it's been four years
since we started trying.
Would you be opposed to me
going to see a specialist?
No.
I'd just like to know
what she says.
Okay.
I thought we were having
spaghetti tonight.
Stove's not working.
You are kidding me.
So we got a leak in the back room,
the dryer only works half the time...
...the car's dying on us
and now the stove's broken.
That's about right.
No wonder I'm losing my hair.
I love you.
And now your
Georgia Sports Break with Alicia Houston.
The Richland Giants
have started football practice...
...as the new school year
gets under way.
The team will be defending a three-year
GISA state championship run.
Now they prepare
to fight for a fourth.
I'm here with head coach
Bobby Lee Duke of the Giants.
Coach Duke, how does
this year look for the team?
Alice, we've grown real fond
of the state title.
And we don't see any reason
to give it up this year.
I've got most of my starters coming back
and I've got a strong bench.
So I've only got
one thing to say:
Get off the tracks,
because the freight train's coming.
Move, move.
I hope that's not a sign of the way
the rest of the season's gonna go, coach.
- Now, why did he have to say that?
- Just let it go.
I hate this car.
Let's find somebody
with jumper cables and let's go home.
It's bad enough you lose your first game.
Now I can't even start my own car.
This happens to everybody.
Don't be embarrassed about it.
Do you have jumper cables?
Oh, sure.
- Grant, I wasn't that embarrassed.
- Then why did you hide?
Why does this house
have to stink so bad?
You'll get used to it
after a couple of hours.
Honey, we gotta do something
about the car.
Because the only thing it does
faithfully for us is break down.
That's about right.
Would it not be better
just to get a small new car?
- You know we can't afford that.
- How do other people do it?
Other people make more
than 24,000 a year.
You make 6000.
That takes us to 30.
Which is enough to help us
with repairs occasionally...
...not with a new car payment.
Besides, there's other bills
we don't normally have to pay.
Like what?
Like my doctor bill.
You saw her today?
- What did she say?
- She said that I'm fine.
My numbers are normal and she saw
nothing that gave her concern.
That's good.
It doesn't mean
the problem is with you.
What else could it mean?
We just may not have
given it enough time.
Four years?
Are you still hoping
we'll have a baby?
You know I am.
Me too.
I catch myself thinking
about it more and more.
Don't you wanna know
if something's preventing it?
Are you afraid
of getting checked out?
Yes.
Grant...
I'm still clinging to a hope
that one day we'll have children.
I imagine them running
in this house.
I hear them playing
in the backyard...
...or running to our bed
in a thunderstorm.
And I think about
reading them stories...
...and teaching them songs.
And I just keep thinking...
...how can I miss someone
so much...
...that I have never met?
I'll go.
Stanley.
Stanley, do you wanna tell me what
you're doing on the top of my desk?
No.
Do you have any idea
how you got on top of my desk?
No.
I suggest
you get down immediately.
You two can tell Coach Taylor that the
reason why you're late for practice today...
...is because you've been
sitting in detention.
Come on, Mrs. Carter.
That was some serious humor.
I'll get serious about your humor
when you get serious about your studies.
Fifty-five?
Well, if you wanna
announce your grade to the entire class...
...you go right ahead.
Fifty-seven.
So basically we got
the toughest schedule we ever had...
...and less talent
than we ever had.
Well, at least we got
Dewey County on Friday night.
That'll be a pretty easy win.
I'm concerned it might be
our only win.
No, we'll pull
three or four out.
That'll give us another
average season.
I'm so sick of average seasons.
- I gotta go.
- Where are you going?
- Got a doctor's appointment.
- For what?
- I have a doctor's appointment.
Leave the man alone.
He don't have to tell you.
So, what's wrong with you, man?
I'll be back in a couple hours.
Now look what you did.
You done made him mad.
Me? You're the one
that made him mad.
No, not me. Besides,
I know where he's going.
Where?
He's going to the hair doctor.
The man is going bald.
You hadn't noticed that whole
underdeveloped region right up in here?
Oh, you're one to talk, Slick.
No, see, when a black man
goes bald, he still looks good.
Look at Michael Jordan,
George Foreman, Samuel L. Jackson.
Classy-looking brothers.
Who you got? Kojak?
Yeah, coach gonna get him
some plugs.
- Grant would not get plugs.
- Don't laugh. You next.
Your soccer skills
get better every year, son.
It doesn't matter, Dad.
Shiloh doesn't have
a soccer team. They play football.
So? Why not kick
for the football team?
They've already got
a good kicker.
I'm sure they wouldn't mind
having two good kickers.
Dad, I'm too small. I really
just don't feel like getting killed.
Are you saying
you're not interested...
...or you'd like to try out
but you're afraid?
What if I don't even
make the team?
Well, you're already
not on the team.
I mean, you can't get any more
not on the team than you are right now.
Okay, Dad.
David, you can't be afraid
of failure.
Everyone fails at some point.
So you think I should try out
for the football team?
Well, if you're waiting around
for soccer, it ain't gonna happen.
Hike.
- Yeah, Sam.
- Yeah, baby.
Coach Owens,
have you got a minute?
Yeah.
Look, some of the men
have been talking.
We really wanna see this school
succeed with our football program.
And I know you feel
the same way too.
But, frankly, we don't ever see that
happening while Coach Taylor is here.
Well, you know we're
in a rebuilding season.
Look, I know he's
a fine man and all...
...but he's had six
years here...
...and nothing significant
to even show for it.
You know, I honestly believe
you would make a better head coach.
Ready to go.
Some of us have requested
a meeting with Mr. Ryker.
If you would just support us,
I really believe this could go a lot easier.
Mr. Pervis, I don't know.
Look, it's not like we're
trying to hurt the guy.
What we're doing is for
the benefit of the school.
You just think about it.
Good hustle, Casey.
What was that about?
What?
Alvin Pervis.
Oh, we were just talking.
- Everything all right?
- Yeah.
Mr. Taylor.
That was great, man. Good job.
Yes.
I'm Larry Childers.
This is my son, David.
He's a junior. We're new
to the school this year.
Good to meet you.
What can I do for you?
Well, I just wanted
to introduce myself to you.
And David wanted to know
if it was too late to try out.
- You a football player?
- Well, I've always played soccer.
But I figured I could
try out as a kicker.
Okay. Well, I got
a pretty good kicker...
...but I don't mind letting you try out.
Jonathan, come here.
This is Jonathan. He holds for
our main kicker, Joshua Webster.
Jonathan, this is David Childers.
He wants to try out as a kicker.
Why don't you two go try a few kicks
just to get your feet wet?
All right, sure.
Thank you, sir. If you don't mind,
I'll just hang around till practice is over.
No problem. Good to meet you.
Y'all just move here?
Yeah, from Athens.
My dad got a job teaching at the college.
That's cool.
I'm used to kicking soccer balls,
but I thought I could at least try out.
Well, Josh is a pretty good kicker,
but he's also a receiver.
I think he likes that better
than kicking. Here you go.
I'm sorry.
Man, I'm sorry.
Ow!
- Sorry about that.
- It's all right.
- Hey, watch it.
- Sorry.
Matt.
- Let's go.
- I'm going with Brock for a little while.
- Not tonight. You're coming home.
- Why?
- Don't argue with me. Let's go.
- No, Dad. I'll be home later.
Matt.
That old man still come every week
to pray in the hallway?
Mr. Bridges. Prays for the students
as he passes their locker.
How long has he been doing that?
He's been praying for revival
since before I got here.
Lord knows we need it.
Apathy in the school's about
as bad as our football record.
Oh, that reminds me.
I think you should go ahead
and let David Childers on the team.
You see something there?
Well, he's just used
to playing soccer.
He ain't that strong,
but he shows promise.
All right. I'll give him a shot.
One, two, hit.
What are you doing? Go.
Let's stay in the game.
No. No.
Will someone tell me how we lost
to Dewey County 21 to 7?
Twenty-one to 7.
Dewey County hasn't beaten Shiloh
since you were in kindergarten.
I don't know what you call that junk
out there, but it sure wasn't football.
Nine dropped passes,
four fumbles, three interceptions.
Their defense scored
most of their points.
You gave the game away.
You can't win football games
if you don't play together as a team.
You can't win games
when you're more concerned...
...about what you're doing
afterwards.
And you can't learn the plays
when you miss practice...
...because you're sitting in detention.
I'm sick of the apathy on this team.
If we're not here to win football
games, then why are we here?
So do you agree with him?
I don't know.
I guess.
Only a few guys on the team
really seem to care.
So are you ready
to play in the game?
I don't know why they would use me
when they've got Joshua Webster.
He can kick
a 45-yard field goal.
I bet you could too.
Dad, I can barely kick
a 35-yard field goal.
At the end of the game,
kind of glad I didn't play.
That way, I can't mess up.
That's fear, son.
I just don't wanna
embarrass the team.
David, I've asked God
since you were a baby
that he would show
how strong he is in your life
and that through you
people would see how good he is.
Then why would he make me
so small and weak?
To show how mighty he is.
Why don't we go ahead and wash up
for dinner? We can finish this later.
All right.
Dad.
Okay. I'm okay.
- What were you doing?
- You missed a spot up there.
Thought I could get it for you.
I guess I got a little too ambitious.
I was just trying
to take a swing at it.
So, um, what does that mean?
I mean, is there a procedure? Or...?
Um, I mean, what are my options?
Grant, first you need to realize this
is a fairly common problem for men.
There are thousands of couples
who are unable to have children.
You do have options.
Although there's only
a 10 percent chance of success...
...many couples have tried
in vitro fertilization.
We can't afford that.
Well, the other option
is to adopt a child.
But it's about as expensive
either way.
If you're interested, I'll put you
in touch with the local agency.
I realize this is difficult
for you to hear.
But at least you and your wife
can make the best decision...
...now that you know
where you are.
Sorry. I didn't realize
anybody was still here.
- Hey, Steve.
- Putting in late hours tonight?
Yeah, I guess so.
I can lock up. You can take off.
All right. Thanks, coach.
It's about the boys now.
I'm not asking you
to throw him out.
If Shiloh can invest
in a winning coach...
...we don't need to be
settling for second best.
You can let him go with
as much class as you want to.
Alvin, he's a good man.
I'm not saying
he's not a good man.
I'm saying he's not
a good coach.
Come on, Dan. Just look at the facts.
His record speaks for itself.
We need new leadership.
I still think
he deserves more time.
More time? He's had six years.
If he was capable of winning,
he'd have done it by now.
Grant Taylor is not capable
of winning.
He doesn't have it in him.
That's the whole point.
Dan, I'm not personally
attacking the coach.
I'm just saying I want my son to have
the best football program possible.
Look, my son's got
a chance for a football scholarship...
...if he's taught
by the right coach.
Matt's gonna be
a senior next year.
I don't wanna see him
lose this opportunity.
Brady, you're awfully quiet.
What's your take on this?
Honestly, I don't know.
Sometimes I think Grant could do a better
job of building this football program.
But then other times,
I think he's doing...
...just as good as anyone
else would in this situation.
Brady, you could do better
than Coach Taylor.
- What we need is a change.
- Now.
We're losing booster support,
game attendance is down...
...and from the looks of it,
we've already lost this season.
That's right.
Dan, we've got a weak program
because we've got a weak coach.
He's dead weight.
We need to cut him loose.
Have you been at school
all this time?
Yes.
I tried to call you an hour ago.
Is everything all right?
Grant, talk to me.
I don't know where to start.
What's going on?
I was trying to lock up for Steve...
...and I overheard Dan meeting
with some fathers.
They didn't know I was there.
Brooke, they're pushing him
to get rid of me.
Neil Prater, Alvin Pervis, Luke Rae.
They said I wasn't capable
of winning.
Called me dead weight.
They can't make Dan fire you.
You've still got support.
You just go get J.T. and Brady
and see him tomorrow.
Brady was there.
They've just lost confidence in me.
You know, I was so sure
I could turn this program around...
...and I've just sunk it lower.
Brooke, I've tried so hard.
Why can't I win?
You can win.
Stop beating yourself up, Grant.
Brooke, I can't provide you
with a decent home.
I can't provide you
with a decent car.
I'm a failing coach
with a losing record.
And I can't give you
the children you want.
What?
It's me.
Like everything else is me.
We can't have our own children
because of me.
What's God doing?
I mean, why is it so hard?
It's okay, Grant.
It's okay.
"I love you, O Lord,
my strength.
The Lord is my rock
and my fortress, my deliverer...
...my God in whom I trust...
...my shield and the horn
of my salvation, my stronghold.
I will call upon the Lord
who is worthy to be praised.
So shall I be saved
from my enemies."
Lord Jesus, would you help me?
I need you.
Lord, I feel like there's giants
of fear and failure
just staring down at me
waiting to crush me.
And I don't know how
to beat them, Lord.
I'm tired of being afraid.
Lord, if you want me to do
something else, show me.
If you don't want me
to have children, so be it.
But you're my guide.
You're on the throne.
You can have
my hopes and my dreams.
Lord, give me something.
Show me something.
If the Lord never
gives us children...
...will you still love him?
Field-goal unit.
Hold on, Joshua. I wanna give David
a shot at this one. David, come here.
This is your field goal.
Put us on the board.
You're gonna go with David?
- Come on, David.
Hit.
Come on.
It's all right, man. It's all right.
You'll get it next time.
Dad, I don't even know why
they let me on the team.
Did you do your best, son?
I knew I was gonna miss it
before I even kicked it.
Your actions will always
follow your beliefs, David.
Dad, I can't even kick it straight.
And I can't walk. Should I just
stay home and pout about it?
If you accept defeat, David,
then that's what you'll get.
Well, Brady,
another fine example...
...of Grant Taylor's
wonderful coaching abilities.
Look, the kids don't deserve it.
The fans don't deserve it.
When you gonna get
a bellyful of this guy?
What's it gonna take?
You got a chance, man.
You got a chance to step in
and take over this program...
...and carry it up for a while.
When are you gonna get
sick and tired of it?
You got an opportunity here.
This program's going in the tank.
Ryker's gotta...
Grant, he came to me.
Brady, you're not doing anybody
any favors sitting on the fence.
You determine which side
you wanna be on and stay on it.
Mr. Bridges.
Revelation Chapter Three says:
"We serve a God that opens doors
that no one can shut...
...and he shuts doors
that no one can open.
He says, 'Behold, I have placed
before you an open door...
...that no one can shut.
I know you have
a little strength...
...yet you have kept my word
and have not denied my name.'"
Coach Taylor, the Lord
is not through with you yet.
You still have
an open door here...
...and until the Lord moves you...
...you're to bloom
right where you're planted.
I just felt led to come
and tell you that today.
Mr. Bridges.
Do you believe God told you
to come tell me that?
I do.
I admit to you
I have been struggling.
But I've also been praying.
I just don't see him at work here.
Grant, I heard a story about two farmers
who desperately needed rain.
And both of them
prayed for rain...
...but only one of them went out
and prepared his fields to receive it.
Which one do you think
trusted God to send the rain?
Well, the one who
prepared his fields for it.
Which one are you?
God will send the rain
when he's ready.
You need to prepare
your field to receive it.
So this is your new
team philosophy?
What do you think?
I think this applies to all of life,
not just football.
Well, that's my point.
Ten bucks to the person
who can tell me...
...who won the state championship
a decade ago.
- Walker Jennings.
- No.
North Metro.
Stop guessing.
You know it or you don't.
- How about five years ago?
- Richland?
That was three years ago.
You can't remember, can you?
Leads me to ask
a couple of questions.
What's the purpose of this team?
Win ball games.
Then what?
We get a trophy.
And people talk about us.
Maybe. For a while.
Then what?
I don't know.
Get a scholarship...
...play for college
and coach Little League.
What are you getting at, Grant?
You think we're just wasting our time?
If our main goal is to win
football games, then yes.
You don't want us to win games?
No.
Not if that's our main goal.
Winning football games
is too small a thing to live for.
And I love football
as much as anybody.
But even championship trophies will
one day collect dust and be forgotten.
It's just that so far
all this has been about us...
...how we can look good,
how we can get the glory.
The more I read this book...
...the more I realize
life's not about us.
We're not here just to get glory,
make money and die.
The Bible says that God
put us here for him.
To honor him.
Jesus said the most important
thing you could do with your life...
...is to love God with everything
you are and love others as yourself.
So if we win every game
and we miss that, we've done nothing.
Football then means nothing.
So I'm here to present you
a new team philosophy.
I think that football is just one
of the tools we use to honor God.
So you think God does care
about football?
I think he cares
about your faith.
He cares about
where your heart is.
If you can live your faith out on the football
field, then, yes, God cares about football...
...because he cares about you.
He sent his son Jesus to die for us
so we could live for him.
That's why we're here.
But, see, it's not just
on the football field.
We've gotta honor him
in our relationships...
...in our respect for authority,
in the classroom...
...and when you're at home alone
surfing the Internet.
I want God to bless this team so much,
people talk about what he did.
But it means we gotta give him
our best in every area.
And if we win, we praise him.
And if we lose, we praise him.
Either way, we honor him
with our actions and our attitudes.
So I'm asking you,
what are you living for?
I've resolved to give God
everything I've got...
...then I'll leave the results
up to him.
I wanna know if you'll join me.
Your attitude's like the aroma
of your heart.
If your attitude stinks,
it means your heart's not right.
- He sure is preachy today.
- Mm-hm.
What?
How's your attitude, Brock?
It's fine.
Then you'll be okay
with the death crawl, right?
All right, everybody on
the goal line. Get your partner. Let's go.
All right, let's go.
Show me something.
Ten yards. Move it, move it.
Let's go, let's go.
Matt, let's go. Let's go, Jonathan.
Show me something. Ten yards.
Show me some power. No knees.
Keep your knees off the ground.
Show me something. Here we go.
Ten yards. Show me some muscle.
Show me some power.
Give me some heart. Let's go.
Very good, boys. Very good.
Let's run it back.
Aw, man! Brock.
Man, that's not
even funny, dude.
Oh, yeah, it is.
So, coach, how strong
is Westview this year?
A lot stronger than we are.
You already written Friday night
down as a loss, Brock?
Well, not if I knew
we could beat them.
Come here, Brock.
You too, Jeremy.
What? Am I in trouble now?
Not yet.
I wanna see you do
the death crawl again...
...except I wanna see
your absolute best.
What? You want me
to go the 30?
- I think you can go to the 50.
- The 50?
I can go to the 50
if nobody's on my back.
I think you can do it
with Jeremy on your back.
But even if you can't I want you
to promise me you're gonna do your best.
All right.
Your best.
- Okay.
- You gonna give me your best?
I'm gonna give you my best.
All right, one more thing.
- I want you to do it blindfolded.
- Why?
I don't want you giving up at a
certain point when you can go further.
Get down.
Jeremy, get on his back.
Now, get a good
tight hold, Jeremy.
All right.
Let's go, Brock.
Keep your knees off the ground.
Just your hands and feet. There you go.
A little bit left.
Come on, Brock. Come on.
There you go.
Show me good effort.
Thattaway, Brock.
You keep coming.
- There you go.
- Come on, Brock.
- Come on.
- It's a good start. Little bit left.
Little bit left.
There you go, Brock.
Good strength.
You gotta be kidding me.
- That's it, Brock. That's it.
- Am I at the 20 yet?
Forget the 20. You give me your best.
You keep going. That's it.
Now don't stop, Brock.
You got more in you than that.
I ain't done.
I'm just resting a second.
You gotta keep moving.
Let's keep moving. Let's go.
Don't quit till you got nothing left.
There you go.
Keep moving. Keep moving.
Keep moving, Brock.
That's it. You keep driving.
Keep your knees off the ground.
Keep driving it. Your very best.
Your very best. Your very best.
Keep moving, Brock.
That's it. That's it. That's it.
Keep going.
Don't quit on me. Keep going.
Keep driving it. Keep your knees
off the ground. That's it.
Your very best.
Don't quit on me. Your very best.
Keep driving. Keep driving.
There you go. There you go.
That's it. You keep driving. Keep your
knees off the ground. Keep driving it.
Don't quit till you got nothing left.
Keep moving, Brock.
That's it. That's it. That's it.
Keep going. I want everything
you got. Come on, keep going.
- It hurts.
- Don't quit on me. Your very best.
Keep driving. Keep driving.
There you go. There you go.
He's heavy.
I know he's heavy.
I'm about out of strength.
Then you negotiate with
your body to find more strength.
But don't you give up on me, Brock.
You keep going, you hear me?
You keep going.
You're doing good. You keep going.
Do not quit on me.
You keep going.
- It hurts.
- I know it hurts. You keep going.
You keep going.
It's all heart from here.
Thirty more steps.
You keep going, Brock. Come on.
- Keep going.
- It burns.
- Then let it burn.
- My arms are burning.
It's all heart. You keep going,
Brock. Come on.
Come on. Keep going.
You promised me your best. Your best.
- Don't stop. Keep going.
- It's too hard.
It's not too hard.
You keep going. Come on, Brock.
Give me more.
Give me more. Keep going.
Twenty more steps.
Twenty more.
Keep going, Brock.
Give me your best. Don't quit.
No. Keep going.
Keep going.
Don't quit. Don't quit.
Don't quit.
Brock Kelley, you don't quit.
Keep going. Keep going.
Go, Brock Kelley. You don't quit
on me. No, you keep going.
You keep going.
Go, Brock.
Ten more steps. Ten more.
Ten more. Ten more.
Keep going. Don't quit.
Give me your heart.
- I can't do it.
- You can. You can.
Five more. Five more.
Come on, Brock. Come on.
Don't quit. Don't quit.
Come on, Brock.
Two more. One more.
That's gotta be fifty.
I don't have any more.
Look up, Brock.
You're in the end zone.
Brock, you are the most
influential player on this team.
If you walk around defeated,
so will they.
Don't tell me you can't
give me more than what I've been seeing.
You just carried a 140-pound man
across this whole field on your arms.
Brock, I need you.
God's gifted you with the ability
of leadership. Don't waste it.
Coach.
Can I count on you?
Yes.
Coach.
What is it, Jeremy?
I weigh 160.
All right. Who's next?
Good practice, boys.
See you all tomorrow.
Hey, man, for the first time in a while,
I actually feel good about Friday night.
Yeah? Why?
I'm just onboard
with what you're doing.
If they get ahold of it,
it'll change their lives.
You count me in.
Grant, me too.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I feel like I owe you
an apology.
I just want you to know
that I'm with you.
Thank you.
See you tomorrow.
- You need a ride, Matt?
- No, my dad's coming.
Or at least, he'd better be.
Can I shoot straight
with you for a minute?
Sure.
I feel like you owe
your dad more respect.
- Why?
- Because he's your father.
- You don't know him like I know him.
- I don't have to know him.
You need to respect him
because it's the right thing to do.
You know, coach,
my dad doesn't even like you.
He thinks the school needs
to find somebody else.
That's beside the point.
Scripture says to honor your parents.
- And all you do is complain.
- All he does is boss me around.
He doesn't even try
to understand me.
Matt, you can't judge
your father by his actions...
...and then judge yourself
by your intentions.
It doesn't work that way.
You're not responsible for him.
You're responsible for you. You honor
God by honoring your authority.
You really believe in all that
honoring God and follow Jesus stuff?
Yes, I do.
Well, I ain't trying
to be disrespectful...
...but not everybody
believes in that.
Religion works
for some people...
...but I'm just here because
I got kicked out of Westview.
Matt, nobody's forcing anything
on you. Following Jesus Christ...
...is a decision you're gonna
have to make for yourself.
You may not wanna accept him.
Because he'll change your life.
You'll never be the same.
I do hope one day you realize
how much he loves you.
I'll see you tomorrow.
Okay. I'll get him.
Just give me the bag.
Just bring that trash bag
over here. Set it down.
Ooh, don't you
let that touch me.
I'm not gonna let him touch you, Brooke.
I'm gonna get him out of here.
Oh, man, he stinks.
Ooh, I can't believe
that was in my house.
- Just make sure it's still dead.
- It's dead.
He's probably been dead
for weeks. Oh, there you go.
You just get it out of here.
Out. Out.
Stop being af... Come here.
- Just look at it.
- Mm-mm. No.
It looks like a big hamster.
- Oh, uh-uh.
- Just... Come here, come here.
Don't be afraid.
Just face your fear. Look.
He's got a cute little tail there.
He's just got a big stink.
Look. See his cute little eyes there?
See his teeth? Look at his teeth.
Almost looks like he's mad.
- Aagghh!
- Oh! Oh!
You're terrible. I can't believe
you did that to me, Grant Taylor.
You are so bad.
Whoo!
David, right down
the middle. You got this.
All right, set it up. Run it again.
Sorry, coach.
David, listen, son.
You act like you gonna miss
before you even kick the ball.
See, we're gonna have to change
your whole kicking philosophy.
Now, see, you're kicking
wide left or wide right.
But that ain't what's gonna
get you home.
The ball has got to go
through the middle.
- I know, coach.
- No. No, you don't.
Now, what does Scripture
say about this?
Um...
Scripture says: Wide is the gate...
...and broad is the way
that leads to destruction...
...and many there be that find it.
Now, to us, that's wide left
and wide right.
Well!
But narrow is the gate and straight
is the way that leads to life...
- ...and few there be that find it.
- Well!
Anybody can kick it
wide left or wide right.
My mama can kick it
wide left and wide right.
But that ain't what's
gonna get you home.
Come on!
It don't have to look pretty.
It don't have to look smooth.
It can look like a dying duck.
But the ball has to go
through the middle.
Oh, my word!
Now, David, you gonna have
to choose the narrow way.
That's the only path where
you will get your reward.
Now send this ball
through these pearly posts.
Set it up one more
time for me, Jonathan.
David, I've never heard it
that way before...
...but there's a lot of truth
to what he's saying.
Let's see you kick it.
Yeah, that's what
I'm talking about.
Grant, are you not aware of what's
going on outside on the field?
What?
You might wanna
come check this out.
Mitch decided to bring
his Bible class outside today.
After he started teaching,
Matt Prater accepted Christ as his Lord.
It was awesome. He started
confessing stuff from his life...
...he started asking his friends
for forgiveness.
Next thing we know, Bob Duke
stands up and does the same thing.
Kids start breaking up into groups,
they begin to pray for each other.
They begin to ask forgiveness
for sins that they've committed.
This has been going on
for three hours.
How did you not know
what was going on?
Bless them in a special way.
Lord, I ask you to lift them up to you.
I ask you to bring up a generation
that has a heart for you, Lord.
Coach.
- I'm proud of you, Matt.
- I need to talk with my dad.
I'd like to go see him.
I'll take you right now.
So, what we've done here
is we've gained these four lots...
...by moving the retention pond
down here.
We could try and do that
through here if you want.
No. I like this.
That's perfect.
Mr. Prater,
there's someone here to see you.
Sarah, I'm in a meeting.
Um, it's your son.
Would you like me to step out?
No, it's okay.
Sarah, send him in.
Matt, you okay?
I'm sorry, Dad. I didn't know
you were in a meeting.
What is it, son?
Uh, Dad, I just wanted
to say that I'm sorry.
I'm sorry for the way
I've been acting.
I got right with God today...
...and I just needed to say
that from now on...
...I'll respect your authority.
Whatever you say goes.
That's it.
You know, I could
come back tomorrow...
...if that would be better for you.
No. It's okay.
I'm sorry. I, uh...
For what it's worth...
...I'd give my right arm
to hear my son say that to me.
I feel like I'm standing
before a new team tonight.
It's a new day and a new game.
What you've experienced
in your hearts this week...
...is about to be released on the field.
Stay humble but confident.
Why don't you
take this one, Brock?
Lord, we know
our lives are not about football...
...but we do thank you
for allowing us to play tonight.
Lord, we're gonna
give you our best.
If we win, we'll praise you,
and if we lose, we'll praise you.
We'll give you all the honor and the glory
for this night, Lord. Keep us safe.
- In Jesus' name we pray. Amen.
- Amen.
All right, guys. Look at me.
Play hard, have fun.
Hit.
Yeah!
In the Old Testament,
Nehemiah had the task of building...
...a stone wall around his city
for protection.
But he didn't have enough people
or resources or time.
But because each person worked on...
...the stone wall
that was in front of their house...
...they got it done in record time.
That's what you're gonna do.
On defense you have to resolve
nothing gets by you as an individual...
...nothing gets by us as a team.
I need you to build me
a stone wall.
Get on that, D.
Yeah.
Let's go. Let's go.
Roll through there like you're
soul-struck. Come on, now.
Come on, Brocky-Brock.
Hit somebody, son.
I wanna see some hitting.
Dig those feet. Come on,
you ain't on my team yet.
You're not on my defense.
You gotta dig those feet.
All right, Prater. Get in there, boy.
Let's go. Hit him.
Hit him, son. You gotta hit him
a little harder than that.
This ain't ballet practice.
This is football practice.
David.
Double-sweep pitch left.
Pro 45 flex. Man, even
a 26 Powerhouse.
Man, these are some good plays.
When we gonna run these plays?
We're gonna run them.
Man, we got all type of potential
on this sheet. When?
- We're gonna run them, I promise.
- Yeah, see?
You always tell me you're gonna
run them. See, all my plays...
- You don't wanna run my plays.
- Hey!
It's all right.
Where's my car?
- Where'd you park it?
- Right here.
You sure? Because there
ain't no way it got stolen.
Man, you couldn't pay
nobody to steal your car.
- Did the boys do something with it?
- Man, I don't know.
Hey, man, there's a note
on this truck for you.
- What does it say?
- Let's see.
It says, "Grant Taylor,
the impact you made on our school...
...means more to us
than you'll ever know.
The Lord has used you
to meet a need in our lives...
...and now we want
to meet a need in yours.
You'll find the title of this
new truck in your name.
Please accept it as our way
of saying thank you."
Uh-uh.
Somebody done gave you a truck?
Man, this title
got your name on it.
You got to be kidding me.
Grant Taylor, somebody
done gave you a new truck.
This is my truck?
Is this just because
you head coach?
Because I'm assistant coach.
You'd think I'd get a moped
out of this or something.
Oh, Lord, you've given me a truck.
Well, it's your truck. Drive it.
Not a word to anyone.
Yes, sir.
That's right.
No more jumper cables.
Break.
Brock. Brock.
- You watch him. You watch him.
- Sure.
Hut, hut.
- Go.
- Go. Go.
That's right. That's it, baby.
You got it, Brock.
That's right.
- Yes, sir? Can I help you?
- Uh, please.
I'd like to buy a nice bouquet
of wildflowers for my wife.
I see.
That's awfully sweet of you.
Oh, yes. I've got a special evening
in mind for her tonight.
Well, in that case, you need a card
to go with those flowers, don't you?
Oh, no. I've already got
the perfect one.
I'm gonna give it to her
at her favorite restaurant this evening.
Oh, really?
I'm sure she'll be happy.
Oh, she will. So I need
your nicest, largest flowers...
- ...and money's no object.
- Oh?
- You see, I got a raise today.
- You did?
- Six thousand dollars.
- Are you serious?
You know, that's exactly the way
my wife's gonna respond.
Oh, Grant!
That's awesome.
You know, you sure got
friendly service here.
Hello again, everybody.
This is Lane Lavarre...
...along with my broadcast
partner, Dale Hansen...
...coming to you tonight from
Princeton Heights Academy...
...the site of tonight's opening round
of the GISA football playoffs.
For the first time
in a decade...
...the Shiloh Eagles find themselves
in postseason play.
And Coach Grant Taylor's
gonna have his hands full tonight...
...as he takes on the
number-one-seeded Panthers...
...who haven't lost
a game all season.
All right, huddle up. Stay sharp,
stay focused, play hard and honor God.
- Eagles on three. One, two, three.
- Eagles.
Sweep.
So after an impressive
seven- and-three record...
...the Shiloh Eagles fall short tonight
in the first round of the GISA playoffs.
Twenty-eight to 10
is the final score.
The Princeton Heights Panthers
take it to the Shiloh Eagles.
I knew we were gonna
get killed tonight.
Your effort was good tonight.
You've got nothing to be ashamed of.
You played hard.
The Shilohs had the best season
they've had in a long time.
God's been good to us this year.
Guys, coach is right.
We're gonna praise God
when we win...
...we're gonna praise him
when we lose.
Let's take a knee.
- Hey.
I wish by some miracle
we could have won tonight.
They worked too hard to walk away
with their heads down.
You know, I was hoping God would
give us just one win in the playoffs.
They deserved it.
You know, if you'd told me
two months ago...
...that we'd be playing
Princeton Heights in the playoffs...
- ...I would not have believed you.
- Yeah.
If you'd told me our school
was having a revival this year...
...I wouldn't have believed you either.
But this ain't been a bad year.
Got all the jerseys?
All 32 of them. But I ain't
ready to put them up, though.
I'm ready to go another round.
You and me both.
Part of me wanted to get to state.
To state?
Grant, are you serious?
Why not? As hard as they worked?
Well, working hard is one thing,
but to take this team to state?
- That'd take an act of God.
- Has he not been acting already?
Well, yeah, he has, but do you know...
...who's gonna be waiting
for whoever gets to state?
- The Richland Giants.
- That's right, the Richland Giants.
And Bobby Lee Duke will be
there with his 85 players...
...ready to spank whoever made it
to the state playoffs to kingdom come.
- I'm not afraid.
- I know you're not afraid.
Because you ain't going.
Oh, by the way, man,
some man called looking for you today.
Who?
Stan Shultz.
- Stan Shultz?
- Yeah.
Stan Shultz.
Isn't that the cartoonist?
That's Charles Schulz.
No, I thought Charles Schulz was
that man that flew across the ocean...
...in the Spirit of St. Andrew.
That's Charles Lindbergh,
and it was the Spirit of St. Louis.
- No, Lindbergh is a cheese.
- Limburger's the cheese.
Lindbergh's the man.
No, Lindbergh was that blimp that
blew up and killed all them people.
That's the Hindenburg.
No, Hindenburg is where
you go skiing in Tennessee.
That's Gatlinburg.
Gatlinburg?
You mean like the country-music
group, the Gatlinburg Brothers?
You guys are crazy.
Grant Taylor.
Well, Mr. Shultz, I was told
you were looking for me.
Yes.
Am I sitting down?
Why do you ask?
Hey, coach,
what's going on here?
Coach is on his way
to let us all know.
All right.
All right, everybody.
Bring it in.
I want you to know
I serve a big God...
...and he can do whatever
he wants to do.
He can open what he wants to open
and shut what he wants to shut.
And a team that plays
for his honor and glory...
...will have his blessings
following that team.
Unlike those who try to cheat their way
to the top, like Princeton Heights did...
...in last Friday's game when they played
two ineligible 19-year-olds.
They have been disqualified
and we're advancing to the next round.
Get your pads on
for practice, boys.
We're going to war
with Tucker Friday night.
Welcome, ladies and
gentlemen, to the GISA quarterfinals.
Who in the world would have thought that
we'd be seeing the Shiloh Eagles tonight...
...in a contest against
the Tucker Tigers?
Well, with Princeton Heights
being disqualified...
...you could call this an early
Christmas present for Shiloh.
Offense, put it in the end zone.
Defense, build me a stone wall.
- Eagles on three. One, two, three.
- Eagles.
Blue, 18. Blue, 18.
Set. Hit. Hit.
David.
This is your field goal.
It belongs to you. Put it through.
We're putting David in.
David.
Hit.
Yeah!
There you go. There you go.
With the clock running down, the
Tucker Tigers are nursing their wounds...
...as they face
the end of their season.
The Eagles, however,
have a little farther to fly.
All right, what kind of sick
are we talking about?
I don't know. I've just felt really
nauseous the last two mornings.
And then I feel fine again.
And you haven't eaten
anything weird lately?
Not unless fruit
and cereal's weird.
Brooke, my gut says make
an appointment with the doctor.
I've been there three times this year.
It's getting embarrassing.
I'm just telling you what I would do.
You can even use my car.
With five seconds left in the game...
...the score still stands
in Oakhaven's favor...
...17-14 over the Eagles.
Grant Taylor calls the play in
to Zach Avery...
...who pulls the huddle together
for their last shot at going to state.
It's third down and goal for the Eagles
and the crowd is going crazy.
They line up in an I formation.
This is do or die for the Eagles.
Zach takes the snap and
will give it to Jacob Hall for...
No, wait a minute, it's a fake.
He's got Nathan Markle open in the
corner. The pass is up. He's got it.
Touchdown Eagles!
Zach Avery completely
faked out the defense...
...and made a perfect pass
to win the game 20 to 17.
Can you believe this?
The Shiloh Eagles are actually
headed to the state championship.
A team with only 32 players
has made it to the big dance. Oh, my.
On the eve of the GISA high-school
football state championship...
...the Richland Giants prepare
to defend their three-year reign...
...as lords of the gridiron.
It's no surprise they've
returned for this game.
What is surprising
is who they're playing.
The Shiloh Eagles, who started the
season 0-3, have come out of nowhere...
...and through an almost bizarre
set of circumstances...
...now face a team
almost three times their size.
Sleep at all last night?
Mm-mm.
Are you nervous?
It's a weird emotion.
Part of me thinks we're
gonna get crushed tonight...
...part of me thinks God may
do something awesome.
Sounds like your fear's
about to clobber your faith.
Hmm. Something like that.
When are you going out there?
I might leave early,
if that's all right.
Yeah, just don't worry about me.
I'll just meet you at the game.
Okay.
Either way, you're still playing
for a state championship.
Hmm.
Juice. There's some juice.
Do you see that?
This is?
- Apple.
- Apple. Good.
- Where's the duck?
- Duck.
- Zebra.
Zebra. Cat.
Duck.
Meow.
There's the pig.
Brooke Taylor's here again.
Aww. Maybe she'll be
pregnant this time.
I hope so.
- You ready, son?
- I can't find my cleats.
They're right here by the door.
Oh, thanks.
You realize you're playing for
the state championship tonight?
I don't know why I'm so nervous.
I'm not even gonna play.
You know I'm proud of you,
don't you?
Yes, sir.
Don't ever doubt it.
Whether you play or not...
...I'll be right there
praying for you.
Thanks, Dad.
Let's go pick a fight
with some giants.
Here's the results
for B. Taylor.
Oh, I'll take that.
Oh.
- Negative?
- Yes.
I will still love you, Lord.
I will still love you.
All right, God.
You got us here.
Whatever happens,
may you get the glory.
Phew.
Coach, what are you doing here?
You're at the state championship.
What do you think I'm doing here?
Any time a former player would get
this far, you know I'd be there.
- No, it blows me away.
- Well, how you feeling?
A little bit nervous.
This championship,
it's kind of surreal for me.
Yeah. Well, I can promise you, I don't care
what level of ball you're coaching...
...it's surreal when you make it
to the championship game.
And, Grant, I can just tell you, I'm so
proud of you and what you've done.
I've been reading about the team
and where you've gone.
And more than anything else...
...I'm just proud of the fact that you
finally learned how to win the big one.
We haven't played them yet.
You won the big one
when you accepted Christ.
And now, as you're teaching
these guys and minister to them...
...I think it's just fantastic.
I got it.
These players got it.
Well, I can promise you, win or lose
this game, you guys are champions.
- I appreciate that.
- But, hey, while you're here...
...you might as well win it, huh?
I'm gonna try my best. You know,
this team we're playing, they're huge.
They're fast, they're strong. I just
don't want my players to be afraid.
Well, in God's word, he said
365 different times, "Do not fear."
If he says it that many times, you know
he's serious about it, don't you?
I would guess so.
I needed to hear that.
Well, look, you're gonna do
great tonight. I know you're busy.
I'm gonna go up in those stands
and cheer you on.
- Good to see you.
- All right. God bless you, man.
Thanks, coach.
In about five minutes
we head out for the warm-up.
I wanna say two things.
Number one,
I love you and I'm proud of you.
I wouldn't trade this season
for anything in the world.
Secondly, you're about to play
the biggest team you've ever faced.
They're strong,
fast and undefeated.
So far.
But I want you to remember
where God has brought us.
I want you to remember
how hard you've worked.
We weren't supposed to have
a winning season, but we do.
We weren't supposed to advance
through the playoffs, but we did.
We're not supposed
to be here, but we are.
So if there's anything in you that says
this is a losing effort, throw it out.
Because as I stand here, I believe
that as long as we honor God...
...nothing is impossible.
Nothing.
Leave everything out on the field.
Give your best to God tonight.
And whether we leave the field the victors
or not, we will give God the glory.
Now...
...who will go fight
the Giants with me?
You've gotta be kidding me.
The Giants elect
to receive after winning the coin toss.
We're just seconds away from the
state-championship football game.
Dale, I gotta tell you. It is impressive
that Shiloh has made it this far...
...but the field tonight
really looks lopsided.
It definitely does.
I'm looking at 85 players
on the Richland sidelines...
...as opposed to 32 for Shiloh.
Even if the Eagles had great talent...
...they can't bring in fresh players
like the Giants can.
That's really gonna hurt them
in the second half.
All right.
Let's go, Joshua.
The Eagles kick off and
the state championship game's underway.
Jerod House will receive the kick
and he'll head down the field.
He gets a couple blocks and breaks
outside. He's got some daylight.
But the Eagles will give chase and they'll
take him down around the 50-yard line.
And that's where the Giants
will set up shop tonight.
First down and 10, in good field position
to start this state championship game.
Get up there. Brock,
watch them up the middle.
Come on. Let's go, boys.
Wes Porter will call the play for
the Giants, and he steps back to pass.
He's got Damien Fuller streaking
down the sideline, and he lets it fly.
Fuller will take the pass in, he will
race into the end zone untouched.
And the Giants strike early here
in the football game with the first score.
Welcome to
state-championship football.
Hey, man, this is
a whole new level.
They are quick off the line.
- We've gotta stay further back.
- I know. I'll adjust.
The Eagles will start this drive
at the 19-yard line.
Zach Avery drops back to pass
and he passes to Jeremy Johnson.
But the pass is batted down
by the Giants.
That's right.
That's the way we do it.
Avery hands it to Jacob Hall,
who tries to run up the middle...
...but he gets absolutely nowhere
as he is swamped by defenders.
Ten, 10, hit, hit.
Eagles look to pass,
but here come the Giants.
And they're gonna get the sack.
And that's gonna force the Eagles...
...into a punting situation
on fourth down.
Whoo! Baby, ain't that
pretty? Whoo!
Jerod House will receive the kick
and he'll head down the field.
He gets a couple blocks and breaks
outside. He's got some daylight.
Okay. All right, time...
Ref, timeout.
After gaining eight yards,
the Eagles give up another sack.
And they're gonna have to
punt it away on fourth down.
Dale, so far tonight
it's been all Richland.
Zach, that was my fault.
I should not have called that play.
Coach, they're all over us.
Nobody's open.
They're knocking us
around out there.
I know they are,
but they're getting cocky.
We cannot let them play their game.
Defense, I want you to blitz on first down.
We've gotta get them
off their rhythm. Let's go.
No!
Field-goal unit.
Let's go, let's go, let's go.
Good job. Good job.
Keep it up.
What universe are you in?
Get in the game.
So with a few seconds left
in the first half...
...it looked as if the Giants were
gonna take a three-touchdown lead...
...but after an Eagles interception,
we've got a 14 to 7 football game.
We can't keep running our normal plays,
man. Their defense is killing us.
I agree. We cannot outmuscle them
and we cannot outrun them.
We've gotta outsmart them.
Trick plays?
Just enough
to keep them guessing.
You see another way?
You just can't use them
too often, though.
They catch on, we toast.
We're toast anyway if we don't
put some points on that board.
We have gotta make it through the fourth
quarter. And they got a deep bench.
First of all,
we're still in this game.
Good job on the defense
getting us on the board.
I believe they thought
this would be a shutout.
We're gonna keep
surprising them.
You've figured out they've got
power and speed, they're big...
...but they're also predictable.
We have gotta stay together.
We can't outrun them,
but we can outsmart them.
With the Giants leading the Eagles 14-7,
we get set to bring you the second half...
...of this state-championship
football game.
And unless the Eagles can find a way
to solve Richland's size and strength...
...the Giants could very well be taking
their fourth consecutive state title tonight.
Make it work, Zach.
And the Eagles come out
with a little trickery.
And they're just about to tie
this football game.
Hustle, hustle. Come on.
Come on. Let's go. Let's go. Let's go.
Make them pay, boys.
Make them pay.
Come on.
That was dirty.
He's hurt. He's hurt. He's hurt.
Joshua Webster's
being helped off the field...
...with what we have been told up here
in the press box is a broken collarbone.
That came after a late hit by the Giants
after the Eagles tied the game at 14 apiece.
- Stupid. That was dirty.
- Hey, calm down.
This is a new ball game.
Joshua's gonna be all right.
David, come here.
You gotta cover for Joshua now.
- I need 110 percent, okay?
- All right, coach.
Be the man.
Kickoff team. Let's go.
Well, after a long drive,
the Giants score.
But the Eagles prevent
the two-point conversion...
...leaving this
a 20 to 14 football game.
Why are they even
on the scoreboard?
They shouldn't even
be in this game.
For the rest of your life,
you will remember today.
I want you to remember that you held
nothing back, you did not lose heart...
...you did not stop fighting,
you did not quit.
They're like little dogs
nipping at your heels.
Now get out there
and stomp them.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's my defense.
Let's go, Eagles.
He's going for a bomb.
Let's go. He's going for a bomb.
Don't get beat. Go.
With seven minutes left on the clock, the
Eagles have shown the determination...
...of a school twice their size.
The Giants will now attempt a 35-yard
field goal to extend their lead.
That is the last time
we go for a field goal.
We should be in the end zone
every stinking time.
Double flex wall.
And hit.
Go. Go. Go.
What are you doing?
Field-goal unit.
Go. Let's go. Let's go.
Let's go.
- Good job. All right.
- That's my team.
Coach, I need a rest.
I can't go much more.
Brock, I need you on that field.
You have gotta stay in the game.
- I need you on the field.
- Yes, sir.
David Childers is in to kick
for Joshua Webster.
We understand that this is his
first season of football...
...and he's gone
three for four this season.
And looking at the stats,
he's been limited to short-range kicks.
Come on, David. You got this.
Yeah.
Timeout, ref. Ref, timeout.
Coach, I'm done.
Someone else has gotta lead.
Brock, this is when it matters most.
I know you're tired.
It's easy to lead
when you're strong.
But now is when you lead us,
right now.
Can you give me four more downs?
I just need four more downs.
Four more.
All right, come here. Come here.
This is our time and you've got
to put the nails in the coffin.
Look at me. Look at me. We didn't fight
this far to give up in the last quarter.
You've gotta leave
everything on the field.
And field goals,
they're not an option.
I need you for four more downs.
Who's with me?
Now get out there and get it done.
With less than two minutes left on
the clock, the Giants stand on the verge...
...of their fourth-straight
consecutive state title.
A tired Eagles team lines up
to face them yet again.
Stone wall. Stone wall.
Yes. Stone wall.
Stone wall.
Stone wall. Stone wall.
The Giants line up first and goal.
This score will solidify
the state championship.
Hand the ball off... No, wait
a minute. He is stopped.
The Eagles are still in it, they're still
showing strong determination...
- to fight this one out.
- Three more downs.
- Three more.
- Yeah!
You gotta hang with me.
I know it's getting tough,
but we've gotta stop them right here.
It's second down
and goal to go for the Giants.
The state title is within their grasp.
Both of the stands are on their feet
as they get ready to run this play.
Wes Porter will take it.
He's gonna try to run it.
No, the Eagles have
stopped him again.
That's my team. That's my team.
Come on.
Get it in the end zone.
Two more.
And here we go again.
They're gonna tee it up and try it again.
Wes Porter will take the snap.
He's looking to pass into the corner.
He's got somebody there.
But, no, the Eagles bat down the pass.
And the crowd is
going nuts right now.
The Giants have been kept out
of the end zone...
...by the Eagles
on three straight plays.
And now Bobby Lee Duke
will have a big decision to make.
Coach, we have gotta
go for a field goal.
We are not going for a field goal.
He's not kicking it. Brock. Brock.
One more down. One more down.
It's fourth down and the Giants
are going for the touchdown.
This crowd is going
absolutely berserk right now.
They line up at the one-yard line.
Wes Porter's gonna take the snap.
They're gonna run it.
Brock Kelley's gonna meet him head-on.
And there's a fumble. There's a fumble.
The Eagles have the football.
They're taking it back down the field.
He's at the 40. He's at the 50.
He's at the 40. And he'll be run
out of bounds at the 34-yard line.
Are you believing this?
With two seconds left on the clock...
...the Eagles have got a shot
at this football game.
Two seconds, Grant.
We've got time for a Hail Mary.
No, no. The defense
is too strong for the pass.
No, we can't run it.
That's our only option.
You gotta kick it, man.
David.
I need a 51-yard field goal.
Coach, I can't kick that far.
David, they've been stopping
the run and the pass all night.
- You're my best option.
- Coach, the farthest I've ever kicked...
...is a 39-yarder. There is no way
I can kick a 51-yard field goal.
I believe you can. Your job
is to do the best you can...
...and leave the results up to God.
I need you on that field.
All right, field-goal unit.
Grant, we've gotta throw it.
He can't kick it from there. It's too far.
- No, it's not.
- What are you doing?
I'm preparing for rain.
I don't understand this,
but with two seconds left on the clock...
...Coach Grant Taylor and the Eagles
are putting the game in the hands...
...of a 145-pound
backup kicker.
This is not
a good move on Grant Taylor's part.
He even has to kick into the wind.
David.
He's not ready, Grant.
He don't think he can do it.
I don't have any more timeouts.
Call a timeout, Bobby Lee.
- This kid can't kick that far.
- Call that timeout.
Call a timeout anyway
and let's ice him.
David, come here.
David, you're telling yourself
you're gonna miss this kick.
Coach, it's too far.
Listen to me. Do you think
God could help you make this kick?
- Do you believe it, David?
- Yeah, if he wants to.
So do I. But you have gotta give him
your best and leave the rest up to him.
Will you do that for me?
David, whether you make this field goal
or not, we're gonna praise him.
But don't you walk off this field
having done any less than your best.
- Can I help you?
- Don't touch me.
I'm standing for my son.
God, help me make this kick.
Kick it now. Kick it now.
Hit.
The kick is up. It's on
its way. It's long enough. It's high enough.
Does it have the distance? It does.
It's good. It's good. It's good.
The Eagles have won. The Eagles
have won the state championship.
Thank you, God.
I can't believe what I've just seen.
I cannot believe what I've just seen.
A miracle has occurred
here tonight.
The Shiloh Eagles have defeated
the Richland Giants 24 to 23...
...to take the state title
for the first time in their history.
It's incredible.
It's absolutely unbelievable.
You are a state champion.
All right.
Who's the state champions?
Okay. Okay.
I got something to say.
David Childers.
Don't you ever let anyone
tell you that you're under par...
...second-rate or inferior.
I just watched God
do a miracle through you.
I saw a field of Giants,
85 of them to be exact, fall in defeat.
Now you tell me what's
impossible with God.
Nothing, coach.
Zach, I just watched you
and the offense do...
...what they said
could not be done.
Now you tell me what's
impossible with God.
Nothing, coach.
Brock, how about it?
You built that stone wall, didn't you?
And it stood.
Now you tell me what's
impossible with God.
- Nothing, coach.
- How about it, Scott?
What's impossible with God?
- Nothing.
- Are you sure?
Because those Giants are big.
They outnumber us three to one.
Are you sure there's
nothing impossible with God?
I'm sure, coach.
How about it, Nathan?
What's impossible with God?
- Nothing, coach.
- Jonathan?
Nothing.
- Are you positive?
- Positive, coach.
So am I. So am I.
God can do whatever he wants to do,
however he wants to do it.
And he chooses to work in our lives
because he loves us...
...because he's good.
Hope today's a milestone for what
he can do for the rest of your life...
...if you trust him.
Why don't we spend some time
thanking him?
Well, look who just
walked in this house.
Couldn't be the state-champion
coach Grant Taylor, could it?
Because he's not
supposed to live here.
He's supposed to be out
looking for a job.
God did it, Brooke.
He did it.
He gave me this job...
...provided for our needs...
...took away my fear.
He throws in the state championship
just because he can.
It's been one of
the best days of my life.
- The day's not over yet.
- What do you mean?
Grant Taylor, I just want you to
know that you've made the team.
What team?
The daddy team.
We're gonna have a baby?
We're gonna have a baby.
You tell me, Coach Taylor...
...tell me what's impossible
when God's on your side?
Oh, God. Oh, God.
I'm overwhelmed.